So today's video is a comparison video
between three plans Niva Bupa Rish 2.0
hdfcergo.com Financial life can be made easy and
happy because the tagline of our company is
also creating a wealth of
happiness, let's move towards the video but
before that if you have not subscribed to our channel then do it so that
you get the right information at the right
time without any further delay, let's
move on to the comparison n b 2.0 hdfcergo.com
Claim settlement ratio hdfcergo.com
ratio is
79.5 aaa Lord Health Advantage's claim
settlement ratio is 88.5% and its claim
ratio is 91.67 so all the three policies have
some unique features, let's talk about them a little
quickly and then we will discuss the rest later
so n b 2.0 has Booster Plus benefit which
means whatever sum assured you are not using is getting carried forward  It
is to the next
year and the maximum it will go up to 10 times. Here
I would like to tell that individual videos of all the three plans are
also available on our channel. If
you want to go into more details, you
can refer there.
I will put the links of that also below. The second
unique point of Niva Bpa is that it is lock the
clock, which means you will lock your age
until you do not make a claim. Your premium will
not increase, it will be locked according to your age.
So lock the clock feature is there. The third
benefit is that in Niva Bpa 2.0
specifically you get disease management rider, which
means if you have pre-existing conditions like BP and diabetes,
then you
can get it covered from 31 days, which
you will not get in the other two plans which we are comparing.
Now let's talk about
hdfcfund.com. You get it every year, it does
not reduce, so once given, given for
life time. The second unique benefit is that here you have
global cover of more than 25 lakhs if you
take a policy.  You also get inbuilt global cover.
You can get treatment outside India as well.
Third is if you
want a maternity policy. Now if you
want maternity coverage in your policy, then
you can add a rider in it. After nine months,
maternity and newborn baby
expenses can also be covered. Now let's talk about
which variants are available.
Three variants are available in n Bup e and 2.0 -
Bronze Plus, Platinum Plus and
Titanium Plus, which is your cover up to 3x,
5x and 10x, which is
Booster Plus benefit hdfcergo.com There is only
one variant in Health Advantage, which is
Apx Plus. Now let's talk about room
eligibility. There is
no room rent restriction in all the three plans. You
can take any room. There is no restriction on age.
Actual pay will be made whether it is room
or IO room. Minimum and maximum entry
age hdfcergo.com
Bonus is basically your No Claim Bonus,
Loyalty Addition, which the company  It also gives you incentives
at the time of renewal. So,
Booster Plus benefit is available in Reassure 2.0. This
means that whatever sum assured you are not using this
year will be carried forward to the next year
and the maximum it will be carried forward up to 10x
depending on the variant you choose. It
grows and will not reduce
if any claim comes in the future.
This is called Guaranteed Sum Assured Bonus. Day
care procedures, home care treatment, AYUSH
hospitalization, domicile treatment
are covered in all these plans up to sum assured.
Refill benefit is basically refill benefit.
It is also called restore benefit, it is
also called reinstatement, it is also
called reassure. It means that if your sum
assured plus bonus gets exhausted in any year, then the
insurance company
gives you refill again. In your policy, there is
Reassure Plus in Niva v Reassure 2.0,
which means that if your
base sum assured or bonus gets exhausted, then you  The
company will refill it again and that
refill will always remain with you as long as you
continue the policy. So this refill is available
in Niva B unlimited number of
times, you can refill it as many times as you want, 101 lakh. If
you have a policy of 10 lakh, you can get it refilled 10 lakh times, if you have a
policy of 20 lakh, then you
can get it refilled every 2020 times.
Once a year refill is available in ADFC Ergo Optima Secure.
If you have a policy of 10 lakh,
then 10 lakh will be refilled again. If the sum is exhausted
in the short policy, then
unlimited restore rider is available which
you can add with a very nominal premium. If you want to add it, you
can do so. Then we are
coming to ICICI Lombard
Advantage. Here refill benefit is available once a year
for any incident like
emergency road ambulance. So in Niva BAP
ReAssure, actual cover will be given on age.
ADFC Ergo Optima Secure  In this also the
actual expenses of ambulance will be given.
In IIC Lombard Health Advantage, % of sum assured is maximum Rs.
10,000 for hospitalization
emergency air ambulance. In Niva Bupa ReAssure, there is a
limit of Rs. 2.5 lakh. In hdfc.com also there is a limit of Rs. 10,000. If we
talk about wellness benefits, that means you
get a discount if you walk steps, then
it is available only in Niva Bupa, which is called Live
Healthy Benefit. So the
number of steps you walk
daily is tracked from your application
and at the time of renewal, you can
also get a discount of up to 30% on your
policy renewal. Pre and post
hospitalization expenses are included
in all three policies. Pre is 60 and post is 180
days e-consultation, so e-consultation
is included. In Niva Bupa, there is unlimited e-consultation.
You can consult doctors
online and second medical opinion is also covered.
For the critical illness for which
you are hospitalized,
e-consultation is available in HDFC Argo Optima Secure
only for the listed 51 critical illnesses.
E-consultation is also included in IAC Lombard,
modern treatments and robotic
surgeries, so modern treatments are
covered up to some extent. In all three policies,
only Niva Bupa ReAssure has a sub-
limit on robotic surgeries. OPD cover is
available as a rider. So if you want to get covered in Niva Bupa, then there is an acute care rider through which you can avail OPD, in which you can consult doctors, get diagnostic tests done and medicines are also reimbursed. A rider has just been introduced in HDFC
Optima Well Being, so this is currently only
for Mumbai, not for other cities,
gradually you will get it in other cities as well. IAC
Lombard Advantage has a rider called
B Fit which is OPD rider which you
can avail if you want OPD coverage.  There is no co-
payment in the policy, so there is no
co-payment in Niva BAP and HDFC.
In ICAC Lombard Health Advantage, if you are taking a policy from Zone 2
or Zone 3, then you will have to pay a
co-payment. If you come to a higher zone and get
treatment, if you do not want to, then
you can take a policy of Zone 1.
If you do not want co-payment, then next
is deductible. Deductible is an option through which
you
can reduce your premium. This is annual agreement.
Get deductible in the context of these
policies. So, it means that you agree to a small
amount that you will pay
before making a claim to the insurance company. At
that time, your premium is reduced
when you are taking the policy.
For example, if you take a deductible of Rs. 50,000, then
you get a discount of 30-40,
which means instead of paying the full premium,
you will pay a discounted premium of 30-40.
But when the claim comes, then the first amount in the year
You will pay the deductible, then the
insurance company will settle all the remaining claims. If you
want to understand the deductible in detail,
I have also shared the calculation on an Excel sheet.
I am also putting that video link below, you
can refer to it. So, the deductible option is available
only in Niva B Rio 2.2 and
global plans in HDFC.com Secure. Now you can
see that you can take it.
In ICICI Lombard, on policies above Rs 25 lakh, there
is global cover, there is worldwide coverage
with a copayment of Rs 10.
Maternity expenses are not covered in Niva BAP and ADAC.
In ICIC Lombard, you
can take Age and Add-ons, in which delivery
expenses, newborn baby coverage and
vaccination expenses are covered.
Now let's talk about optional riders.
Which riders are available in your policy,
which you can take by paying an additional premium.
So, in Niva BAP Reassure, there is a
safeguard which covers your  Non-payable items
Safeguard Plus in which all non-payable
items are covered, the entire list is covered
basically, then your acute care which
is OPD rider, hospital cash benefit which
gives daily cash benefit for the number of days you are
hospitalized, there is personal accidental
rider which covers your accidental death and
disability, there is disease management
rider where from 31 days you can get BP and
diabetes pre-assisting conditions covered,
hdfcergo.com will be opened for other cities as well, there is a
fit rider in ISA loan which is
OPD rider, claim protector
which covers your non-payable items,
sum in short protector which
gives the impact of health inflation on your sum in short, and
maternity benefits which we talked about in
which delivery cost, newborn baby
expenses, vaccination expenses can be covered, you
can choose personal accidental rider and critical illness rider, keep in
mind that the more riders you add, the more the
premium will increase  So
add only those riders which you actually
need. Now let's talk about the
coverage of waiting periods. We have already talked about the coverage of waiting periods, but
talking about waiting periods is equally
important. The initial waiting period is
30 days in all three policies. You cannot avail planned hospitalization till 30 days.
Slow growing illnesses specified
exclusions are not covered for two years. All three
policies have a waiting period of 24 months.
Pre-assisting conditions are
three years in Niva Bupa Rish 2.2. If you
take the disease management rider, then
your BP and diabetes are covered from 31 days.
ADAC Ergo Optima Secure also has a
waiting period of three years for pre-assisting conditions. ICC Lombard has a waiting period of two
years for pre-assisting conditions.
Now let's finally talk about the
premium. How much do these plans actually
cost you? This is the premium,
you can check it on your screen.  And you
can choose which plan
is suitable for you on the basis of features, on the basis of premium
and what riders you want, what
is necessary for you. So this was my
ultimate comparison between three most
demanded plans n b 2.0 hdfcergo.com
Want health insurance consultation, you can contact us
[Music]